export interface Qstn {
  question: string;
  options: string[];
  correctOption: number;
  points: number;
}
export  const qstns: Qstn[] =[
    {
      "question": "What does kemish love mostly for his dinner?",
      "options": ["cauli", "roast", "simple rice", "fried potato"],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 5
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is the longest river in Earth?",
      "options": ["Nile", "Amazon", "Koshi", "Singzilla"],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "First IT college of Nepal?",
      "options": ["Lord buddha Education foundation", "ISMT", "NIST", "Tribhuwan IT college"],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "How many districts are there in Nepal?",
      "options": ["74", "75", "76", "77"],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "To visit Mustang  from ktm,how many districts you have to cross?",
      "options": ["3", "4", "5", "6"],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the ancient Greek god of the Sun?",
      "options": ["Thomas", "Edison", "Aleander The Great", "Apollo"],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which country is Nepal bordered in the Sout West?",
      "options": ["India", "Bangaladesh", "China", "USA"],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which place has the highest number of ports?",
      "options": [
        "ktm",
        "Delhi",
        "Beirut",
        "Varanasi"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "When was PN shah born?",
      "options": ["1779", "1780", "1781", "1778"],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the next number in the series: 2, 4, 6, 8, 18, 16, ___?",
      "options": [
        "24",
        "30",
        "32",
        "54"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "Which language has the most native speakers?",
      "options": [
        "English",
        "Spanish",
        "French",
        "Hindi"
      ],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "If a plane crashes on the border of the United States and Canada, where do they bury the survivors?",
      "options": [
        " United States",
        "Canada",
        "Nowhere, survivors are not buried",
        "In a cemetery"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "I was born in January, when i was 4 my sis was 2.Now i am 6, my sis is?",
      "options": [
        "2",
        "3",
        "4",
        "5"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the singer of moye moye song?",
      "options": [
        "Blackpink",
        "Dilher mehendi",
        "Atif aslam",
        "Dzanum"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 5
    },
   
    {
      "question": "Orange is?",
      "options": [
        "A color",
        "A colour",
        "Frut",
        "Steam"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 30
    },
   
    {
      "question": "Pythagorous is?",
      "options": [
        "A name",
        "A mathematical word",
        "A surname",
        "I dont know."
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "if a sun goes blackout and again shines how much time we would be without sunlight?",
      "options": [
        "8 seconds",
        "8 minutes",
        "8 days",
        "8 weeks"
      ],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 10
    }
  ]

export default qstns;